<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Robert Lemos</title>
    <description>Technology journalist/data and dev geek
</description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 09:34:26 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Dec 2023 09:34:26 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.9.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 51 in Review: Zoom's VISS and a Surge in Zero-Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A lot of writing this past week, but most of which won’t be published for the next few weeks, since my editors are caching articles for the coming vacation. So, I have two articles to post from the past week: One covering the differences of Zoom’s new Vulnerability Impact Scoring System, and another for README.security that is focused on the surge in 0-day vulnerabilities over the past year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;will-putting-a-dollar-value-on-vulnerabilities-help-prioritize-them--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/putting-dollar-value-vulnerabilities-prioritize&quot;&gt;Will Putting a Dollar Value on Vulnerabilities Help Prioritize Them? | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Zoom’s Vulnerability Impact Scoring System calculates the impact of a vulnerability to assign a cash payout for bugs, leading hackers to prioritize more severe flaws. Can it do the same for companies? (18 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;zero-days-arent-just-for-nation-states-anymore--readmesecurity&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://readme.synack.com/zero-days-arent-just-for-nation-states-anymore&quot;&gt;Zero-days aren’t just for nation-states anymore | README.security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In 2023, attackers continue to wield more zero-day exploits against companies and individuals, using them for ransomware, surveillance and espionage. Will the number of zero-days climb further in the New Year? What can organizations do? (21 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/22/week-in-review-51/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/22/week-in-review-51/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 50 in Review: LinkedIn scams target Middle East, and an introduction to CVSS 4.0</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had two articles published this week, one over at Dark Reading covering the relative improvement in LinkedIn scams targeting the Middle East and another for Synack’s README.security covering the release of CVSS 4.0.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;cvss-40-is-shaking-up-vulnerability-management-heres-whats-changed--readmesecurity&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://readme.synack.com/cvss-4-is-shaking-up-vulnerability-management.-heres-whats-changed&quot;&gt;CVSS 4.0 is shaking up vulnerability management. Here’s what’s changed | README.security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;CVSS 4.0 urges companies to go beyond base scores, allowing them to more accurately judge the threat posed by particular vulnerabilities based on threat intelligence and environmental factors. (14 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;convincing-linkedin-profiles-target-saudi-workers-for-information-leakage--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cloud-security/convincing-linkedin-profiles-target-saudi-workers-information-leakage&quot;&gt;Convincing LinkedIn ‘Profiles’ Target Saudi Workers for Information Leakage | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Social engineering attacks in the Kingdom collect information on professionals — and offer fake profiles for sale. (11 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/15/week-in-review-50/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/15/week-in-review-50/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 49 in Review: Cloud security in the Middle East, and OT ransomware</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had four articles published this week. The top story was based on analyses from Palo Alto Networks and Microsoft that showed that the Russian hacking group known as Fancy Bear had continued to use a Microsoft Outlook zero-click vulnerability as late October this year. In other articles, I looked at ransomware’s growing impact on operational technology, and worries over the criticality of cloud operations to the security of companies in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;russian-espionage-group-hammers-zero-click-microsoft-outlook-bug--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/russian-espionage-group-hammers-zero-click-microsoft-outlook-bug&quot;&gt;Russian Espionage Group Hammers Zero-Click Microsoft Outlook Bug | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;State-sponsored actors continue to exploit CVE-2023-23397, a dangerous no-interaction vulnerability in Microsoft’s Outlook email client that was patched in March, in a widespread global campaign. (8 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ransomware-data-breaches-inundate-ot--industrial-sector--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/ransomware-data-breaches-inundate-ot-industrial-sector&quot;&gt;Ransomware, Data Breaches Inundate OT &amp;amp; Industrial Sector | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Because of the criticality of remaining operational, industrial companies and utilities are far more likely to pay, attracting even more threat groups and a focus on OT systems. (7 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;middle-east-cisos-fear-disruptive-cloud-breach--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cloud-security/middle-east-cisos-fear-disruptive-cloud-breach&quot;&gt;Middle East CISOs Fear Disruptive Cloud Breach | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Increasingly, businesses are concerned about the speed of their cloud incident response times. (6 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;enhancing-incident-response-playbooks-with-machine-learning--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/automation-via-machine-learning-makes-cybersecurity-playbooks-better&quot;&gt;Enhancing Incident Response Playbooks With Machine Learning | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cybersecurity analysts use playbooks as a guide to quickly investigate and respond to incidents, but they regularly neglect to keep the process documents up to date. (5 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/08/week-in-review-49/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/08/week-in-review-49/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 48 in Review: Ransomware in the Middle East, law firms under fire</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Only two articles out this week. As part of Dark Reading’s increased focus on the Middle East and Africa, I covered the surge in ransomware and other threats due to both geopolitics and attacker’s efforts to go where the money is. In a similar vein, law firms and other legal departments have become a popular target for hackers, especially the Blackcat group, which uses SEO based on legal terms to target lawyers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;law-firms--legal-departments-singled-out-for-cyberattacks--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/law-firms-face-a-more-dangerous-threat-landscape&quot;&gt;Law Firms &amp;amp; Legal Departments Singled Out for Cyberattacks | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cybercriminals use legal search terms to ensnare unwitting victims, then launch ransomware or business email compromise attacks. (30 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-ransomware-could-surge-in-the-middle-east--africa--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/ransomware-attacks-strike-south-africa-decline-in-uae&quot;&gt;Why Ransomware Could Surge in the Middle East &amp;amp; Africa | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Organizations from the Middle East and Africa have typically escaped public ransoms, but that’s changing amid heightened geopolitical conflicts and digitalization initiatives. (29 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/01/week-in-review-48/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/12/01/week-in-review-48/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 47 in Review: A look at the KEV list, a Kubernetes rootkit, and web shells</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Thanksgiving to those who celebrate it. This week, Dark Reading published three articles, including coverage of the strengths and weaknesses of the the Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV) list, a rootkit that does more than cryptomining on compromised Kubernetes clusters, and a new web shells with some advanced features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;web-shells-gain-sophistication-for-stealth-persistence--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/cloud-security/web-shells-gain-sophistication-for-stealth-persistence&quot;&gt;Web Shells Gain Sophistication for Stealth, Persistence | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A favorite post-exploitation tool continues to gain sophistication, with one recent example adding disguised log-in pages, credential stealing, and information gathering via services such as VirusTotal. (22 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rootkit-turns-kubernetes-from-orchestration-to-subversion--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/rootkit-turns-kubernetes-from-orchestration-to-subversion&quot;&gt;Rootkit Turns Kubernetes from Orchestration to Subversion | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kubernetes compromises have usually led to attackers creating cryptomining containers, but the outcomes could be much worse, say researchers presenting at the Black Hat Europe conference. (22 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;exploited-vulnerabilities-can-take-months-to-make-kev-list--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/exploited-vulnerabilities-can-take-months-to-make-kev-list&quot;&gt;Exploited Vulnerabilities Can Take Months to Make KEV List | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Known Exploited Vulnerabilities (KEV) catalog is a high-quality source of information on software flaws being exploited in the wild, but updates are often delayed, which means companies need other sources of threat intelligence. (19 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Nov 2023 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/24/week-in-review-47/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/24/week-in-review-47/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 46 in Review: Molerats Change Tactics, Flaws in AI Tools, Developers Under Attack</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I covered the Molerats group’s adoption of a more advanced payload for its espionage campaign, more than dozen vulnerabilities found in an handful of popular AI tools, and a README feature on the targeting of developers through the software supply chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unpatched-critical-vulnerabilities-open-ai-models-to-takeover--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/unpatched-critical-vulnerabilities-ai-models-takeover&quot;&gt;Unpatched Critical Vulnerabilities Open AI Models to Takeover | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The security holes can allow server takeover, information theft, model poisoning, and more. (16 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;attackers-see-developers-as-low-hanging-fruit--readmesecurity&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://readme.synack.com/attackers-see-developers-as-low-hanging-fruit&quot;&gt;Attackers see developers as low-hanging fruit | README.security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Developers must be increasingly wary of actively malicious code that makes its way into their software supply chains. (15 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;molerats-group-wields-custom-cybertool-to-steal-secrets-in-the-middle-east--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/dr-global/molerats-group-wields-custom-cyber-tool-to-steal-secrets-in-middle-east&quot;&gt;Molerats Group Wields Custom Cybertool to Steal Secrets in the Middle East | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The so-called TA402 group continues to focus on cyber espionage against government agencies with the “IronWInd” malware. (14 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 15:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/17/week-in-review-46/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/17/week-in-review-46/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 45 in Review: Mainframes, AI, and 'Shields Ready'</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;My articles this weeks spanned the seemingly old (mainframes), the seemingly new (vulnerability-fixing AIs), and the never-ending effort to stop bad guys, this time with a focus on critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;shields-ready-critical-infrastructure-initiative-addresses-inevitable-cyberattacks--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot/shields-ready-initiative-inevitable-cyberattacks&quot;&gt;‘Shields Ready’ Critical Infrastructure Initiative Addresses Inevitable Cyberattacks | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A cyberattack is coming, disasters are certain, and the US government wants critical infrastructure firms ready to handle any disruption. Welcome to Shields Ready. (10 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;first-wave-of-vulnerability-fixing-ais-available-for-developers--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/emerging-tech/first-wave-vulnerability-fixing-ai-available-developers&quot;&gt;First Wave of Vulnerability-Fixing AIs Available for Developers | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;GitHub joins a handful of startups and established firms in the market, but all the products are essentially “caveat developer” — let the developer beware. (9 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;software-complexity-bedevils-mainframe-security--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/dr-tech/software-complexity-bedevils-mainframe-security&quot;&gt;Software Complexity Bedevils Mainframe Security | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The high-performance and resilient platforms satisfy critical roles, but software complexity and the graying of the specialist workforce are creating security challenges. (7 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/10/week-in-review-45/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/10/week-in-review-45/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Website is back</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple of weekends ago, I moved over my domain and mail infrastructure to new providers, so I decided to use the momentum to get my blog back up and running on GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog is based on the theme Writer, originally from ThemeForest in 2016, but the theme appears to have disappeared.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-docker-for-jekyll&quot;&gt;Using Docker for Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I try not to download a lot of crud when developing and doing web work, so I really like to run a lot of my code through Docker containers. In this case, I use Jekyll to build and host the site locally, while I work on it, and then push the files in the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; directory to GitHub Pages for hosting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do this also with my datascience work as I can then also provide the Dockerfile and docker-compose files to the client so they can easily reproduce any work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;four-steps-to-a-more-private-blog&quot;&gt;Four steps to a more private blog&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since I didn’t want to publish my source code for the blog (along with potential development secrets) to the public repository where my blog lives, I needed to do a bit of git-wrangling to make it all work. My process is based on &lt;a href=&quot;https://scriptedtea.com/tech/how-to-deploy-jekyll-to-github/&quot;&gt;an organization and workflow described by Scripted Tea in 2019&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The basic setup process for setting up the blog is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Download a theme, move any custom files (such as any &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt;) to the new directory,&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run the Jekyll server on the files to build the Jekyll site and populate the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; files, and&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Push the local directory to a repository on GitHub to keep the project organized.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To initialize the blog, I excluded the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; directory using .gitignore, and then initialied git within the directory, switched to the gh-pages branch, and cloned that directory with the public blog repo on GitHub.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, the result of all this is a Git repository within a Git repository, with the web files created by Jekyll synced with the public blog, and the entire project synced with a private GitHub project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-process-going-forward&quot;&gt;The process going forward&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the future, when I add a post to the blog, I can run Jekyll locally to see the blog in action, and when I’m done with updates and changes, I can move into the &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder and commit the changes, which will populate the blog again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the CLI steps:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-{bash}&quot;&gt;$ cd Sites/{blog directory}
$ docker-compose up    // this generates the Jekyll files and serves them locally
$ cd _site
$ git add .
$ git commit -m &quot;Blog deployment - {date}&quot;
$ git push origin gh-pages
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, there is a still a bunch to do to the blog to make it better, but at least I solved the workflow issues, which is half the battle. I have a lot of customizing to do on the theme, as well as making sure all the templates are displaying as they should.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/05/blog-back-up-and-running/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/05/blog-back-up-and-running/</guid>
        
        <category>gtd</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
        <category>development</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 44 in Review: Budget Cuts to Hit CISA, Cybersecurity Jobs Report</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I mainly focused on the economy in my published reports this week. Both articles are for Dark Reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;isc2-study-economic-conditions-continue-to-sandbag-cyber-hiring--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/careers-and-people/cybersecurity-s-continued-shortfall-not-proof-against-layoffs&quot;&gt;ISC2 Study: Economic Conditions Continue to Sandbag Cyber Hiring | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nearly 1.5 million people work in cybersecurity in North America, but even with a growing gap in skilled specialists, they bear a higher chance of hiring freezes and layoffs. (1 November 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;budget-cuts-at-cisa-could-affect-enterprise-cybersecurity--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/edge/budget-cuts-at-cisa-could-affect-enterprise-cybersecurity&quot;&gt;Budget Cuts at CISA Could Affect Enterprise Cybersecurity | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Politicians are suggesting massive cuts to CISA’s budget, threatening its missions to secure federal networks and help critical infrastructure operators fend off cyberattacks. (30 October 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 10:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/03/week-in-review-44/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/11/03/week-in-review-44/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week 43 in Review: Rockwell Buys Cybersecurity, SMS 2FA Still Sticky</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A breach of at least one developer on the Steam game platform led Valve, the owner of Steam, to required a cell number for every developer for 2-factor authentication, despite the fact that SMS is considered to be the least secure second-factor. Meanwhile, the industrial control industry continues to partner or purchase cybersecurity services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rockwells-verve-buy-enlivens-critical-infrastructure-security--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot/rockwell-verve-buy-critical-infrastructure-security&quot;&gt;Rockwell’s Verve Buy Enlivens Critical Infrastructure Security | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The industrial automation giant agrees to buy Verve Industrial Protection, joining in an ICS trend of bringing cybersecurity capabilities in-house to keep up with attackers. (26 October 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;valves-2fa-mandate-for-game-developers-shows-sms-stickiness--dark-reading&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/valve-2fa-mandate-game-developers-sms-stickiness&quot;&gt;Valve’s 2FA Mandate for Game Developers Shows SMS Stickiness | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despite warnings that sending one-time passwords via text messages is a flawed security measure, companies continue to roll out the approach, especially in consumer-facing applications. (23 October 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 10:44:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/27/week-in-review-43/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://0.0.0.0:4000/2023/10/27/week-in-review-43/</guid>
        
        <category>week-in-review</category>
        
        
        <category>articles</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
