<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Robert Lemos - Robert Lemos</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://robertlemos.com/feeds/robert-lemos.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://robertlemos.com/</id><updated>2025-08-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated><subtitle>writer, journalist, coder, data analyst</subtitle><entry><title>Week in Review — LLM-Generated Code Not Secure, Africa Under Attack</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2025/week-in-review-llm-generated-code-not-secure-africa-under-attack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-08-02T09:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-08-02T09:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2025-08-02:/2025/week-in-review-llm-generated-code-not-secure-africa-under-attack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Veracode study of over 100 large language models (LLMs) across 80 coding tasks found &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/llms-ai-generated-code-wildly-insecure"&gt;only about 55% of AI‑generated 
code passed security scans&lt;/a&gt; —
even though over 90% now compile without error. Java was especially problematic, with a 
vulnerability rate above 45%, while developers also encountered frequent issues like …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A Veracode study of over 100 large language models (LLMs) across 80 coding tasks found &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/llms-ai-generated-code-wildly-insecure"&gt;only about 55% of AI‑generated 
code passed security scans&lt;/a&gt; —
even though over 90% now compile without error. Java was especially problematic, with a 
vulnerability rate above 45%, while developers also encountered frequent issues like slopsquatting — LLMs hallucinating 
nonexistent libraries—and susceptibility to prompt injection. The report warns against “vibe coding,” where developers 
rely on AI without embedding security requirements, urging organizations to integrate security checks, remediation 
tools, and developer training into AI‑driven workflows to avoid accumulating long‑term security debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A security researcher found that Azure Logic Apps’ API Connections &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/low-code-tools-azure-allowed-unprivileged-access"&gt;sometimes permitted users with read‑only or 
unauthenticated privileges to access sensitive data&lt;/a&gt; 
across other applications and infrastructure components. The vulnerability arises 
because while Azure Resource Management (ARM) properly restricts low‑privilege users to GET requests, the underlying 
API Connection objects do not consistently honor those restrictions, enabling broader access than intended.
The issue was discovered by Binary Security’s Haakon Gulbrandsrud and will be detailed at Black Hat USA; 
Microsoft has since patched the flaw, but the finding emphasizes the need for explicit oversight of auto-generated 
API Connections in low-code Azure deployments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting July 22, multiple African organizations including South Africa’s National Treasury, local government entities, 
universities, and private firms were &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/african-orgs-mass-microsoft-sharepoint-exploits"&gt;compromised through widespread exploitation of four related on-premises SharePoint 
vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt; dubbed 
"ToolShell." While initial targeting was likely by China-linked cyberespionage groups, later 
attacks became opportunistic—scanning exposed SharePoint servers indiscriminately across Africa and beyond, exploiting 
systems before patches were applied. The incident underscores Africa’s expanding digital infrastructure and reliance on 
on‑premises software, emphasizing urgent needs for layered defenses, rapid patching, vulnerability management, and 
better monitoring to prevent future mass intrusions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="Africa"></category><category term="cybersecurity"></category><category term="articles"></category><category term="cyberattacks"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — India Struggles to be Cyber-Secure, Humanitarian Orgs Under Attack</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2025/week-in-review-india-struggles-to-be-cyber-secure-humanitarian-orgs-under-attack.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-06-14T09:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-14T09:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2025-06-14:/2025/week-in-review-india-struggles-to-be-cyber-secure-humanitarian-orgs-under-attack.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Indian security leaders are struggling to modernize cybersecurity operations amid rapid AI adoption, 
an expanding attack surface, and a shortage of skilled professionals — 
&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/india-security-leaders-struggle-threats"&gt;leaving critical blind spots in threat detection&lt;/a&gt;. 
Meanwhile, compliance demands are stacking up too: the new 2025 Data Protection Rules require breach notifications within six 
hours and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Indian security leaders are struggling to modernize cybersecurity operations amid rapid AI adoption, 
an expanding attack surface, and a shortage of skilled professionals — 
&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/india-security-leaders-struggle-threats"&gt;leaving critical blind spots in threat detection&lt;/a&gt;. 
Meanwhile, compliance demands are stacking up too: the new 2025 Data Protection Rules require breach notifications within six 
hours and coordination across multiple regulators, adding layers of complexity. To respond, experts recommend 
strengthening core cyber hygiene (like MFA and patching), footing an AI‑powered SOC, and investing heavily in 
workforce reskilling to keep pace with evolving threats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cyberattacks targeting humanitarian, environmental, activist, and journalism organizations have surged 
dramatically — &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/attacks-humanitarian-orgs-jump-worldwide"&gt;rising approximately 241% over the past year&lt;/a&gt;
— with DDoS attacks the most prevalent tactic. These nonprofit and civil-society groups are especially vulnerable 
due to limited cybersecurity budgets and resources, with only around 15% having any dedicated cybersecurity expertise 
on staff. The report highlights that threats come from diverse actors—including state-backed operatives, 
ideologically driven hacktivists, and opportunistic cybercriminals—underscoring a pressing need for stronger defenses 
and targeted security support for these critical organizations.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="India"></category><category term="cybersecurity"></category><category term="articles"></category><category term="cyberattacks"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — Naming with Microsoft and CrowdStrike, Cybersecurity Training in Africa</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2025/week-in-review-naming-with-microsoft-and-crowdstrike-cybersecurity-training-in-africa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-06-07T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-06-07T12:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2025-06-07:/2025/week-in-review-naming-with-microsoft-and-crowdstrike-cybersecurity-training-in-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and CrowdStrike have 
&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/microsoft-crowdstrike-rosetta-stone-apt"&gt;launched a joint initiative&lt;/a&gt;
to harmonize the naming of cyber threat groups, aiming to 
reduce confusion caused by differing labels across security vendors. By publishing a mapping of over 80 threat actor 
aliases, such as aligning Microsoft's "Canary Typhoon" with CrowdStrike's "Circuit Panda," they seek to …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Microsoft and CrowdStrike have 
&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/microsoft-crowdstrike-rosetta-stone-apt"&gt;launched a joint initiative&lt;/a&gt;
to harmonize the naming of cyber threat groups, aiming to 
reduce confusion caused by differing labels across security vendors. By publishing a mapping of over 80 threat actor 
aliases, such as aligning Microsoft's "Canary Typhoon" with CrowdStrike's "Circuit Panda," they seek to streamline 
threat intelligence and improve response times. However, this effort faces skepticism, as similar attempts have been 
made before, and questions remain about its effectiveness in addressing emerging threats and achieving broader 
industry adoption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With a rise in cyberattacks — up 23% in 2023 — and a severe shortage of cybersecurity professionals, international 
organizations are collaborating with nations throughout the continent on initiatives like the UNDP's Tech4Peace and 
Carnegie Mellon University's picoCTF-Africa. The collaborative efforts are &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/cybersecurity-training-africa-professionals-ranks"&gt;training thousands of students across 
the continent&lt;/a&gt; 
in cybersecurity skills. These programs aim not only to bolster digital defenses but also to provide economic 
opportunities and deter youth from joining armed groups.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="Africa"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — CISO Peaking, India Arrests Cybercrime Gang</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2025/week-in-review-ciso-peaking-india-arrests-cybercrime-gang.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2025-05-31T12:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2025-05-31T12:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2025-05-31:/2025/week-in-review-ciso-peaking-india-arrests-cybercrime-gang.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite rising compensation and expanded responsibilities, CISOs &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/ciso-stature-rises-budgets-tight"&gt;face challenges due to tight security budgets&lt;/a&gt;. A survey 
by IANS Research indicates that CISOs at large U.S. companies earn an average of $532,000, reflecting their growing 
role in assessing business risk and digital strategy. However, budget approvals are more likely …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Despite rising compensation and expanded responsibilities, CISOs &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/ciso-stature-rises-budgets-tight"&gt;face challenges due to tight security budgets&lt;/a&gt;. A survey 
by IANS Research indicates that CISOs at large U.S. companies earn an average of $532,000, reflecting their growing 
role in assessing business risk and digital strategy. However, budget approvals are more likely when expenditures are 
directly linked to business growth initiatives, highlighting the need for CISOs to align security efforts with 
organizational objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Indian police in the state of Andhra Pradesh &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/indian-police-arrest-cybercrime-gang-copycats-myanmar-biz-model"&gt;dismantled a cybercrime operation modeled after Southeast Asian scam centers&lt;/a&gt;, 
arresting 33 individuals and detaining over 100. Operating from the Atchutapuram Special Economic Zone, the group ran 
fake call centers impersonating Amazon support to defraud victims in the US, UK, and Australia. Experts attribute 
the proliferation of such syndicates in regions like India to factors such as a large pool of tech workers, 
economic disparities, and weak cybercrime law enforcement.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="India"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="CISOs"></category><category term="Asia"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Comic Collaboration — Newbie-ginnings and In Plain Sight</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/comic-collaboration-newbie-ginnings-and-in-plain-sight.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-05-22T00:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-05-22:/2024/comic-collaboration-newbie-ginnings-and-in-plain-sight.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;In February, I saw a call for proposals to submit a story — of up to 5 pages — for comic anthology being produced 
by Green Archer Comics, a small outfit whose founders have some cybersecurity roots. I asked if they were still 
interested in submissions. (They were.) So I asked my …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;In February, I saw a call for proposals to submit a story — of up to 5 pages — for comic anthology being produced 
by Green Archer Comics, a small outfit whose founders have some cybersecurity roots. I asked if they were still 
interested in submissions. (They were.) So I asked my daughter — a double major in computer science and media arts — 
if she would be interested in doing the comic. (She was.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, after a weekend of brainstorming, I came up with a story and passed it along to her. My few hours of work ended up
being dozens of hours of drawing for her. I think the effort came out great. Both of us had never done a comic before, 
so it was a phenomenal experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The anthology is &lt;a href="https://www.greenarcher.io/newbie-ginnings"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Newbie-ginnings: A Cybersecurity Comic Anthology&lt;/em&gt; from Green Archer Comics&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="My Works"></category><category term="cybersecurity"></category><category term="comics"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — NASA Zero-Trust, UAE Vulnerabilities, and Software-Defined Cars</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-nasa-zero-trust-uae-vulnerabilities-and-software-defined-cars.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-15T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-03-15T17:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-03-15:/2024/week-in-review-nasa-zero-trust-uae-vulnerabilities-and-software-defined-cars.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The NSA's zero-trust guidelines and the exposure of over 150,000 vulnerable devices in the UAE highlight 
the growing need for enhanced cybersecurity across industries, especially as misconfigurations and insecure 
services leave critical infrastructures at risk. Meanwhile, the rise of software-defined cars and the rapid 
adoption of AI models introduce …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The NSA's zero-trust guidelines and the exposure of over 150,000 vulnerable devices in the UAE highlight 
the growing need for enhanced cybersecurity across industries, especially as misconfigurations and insecure 
services leave critical infrastructures at risk. Meanwhile, the rise of software-defined cars and the rapid 
adoption of AI models introduce new attack surfaces, further emphasizing the need for visibility and robust 
security measures in both traditional and emerging technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/6-ciso-takeaways-nsa-zero-trust-guidance"&gt;6 CISO Takeaways From the NSA's Zero-Trust Guidance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All companies — not just federal agencies — should aim to adopt the "network and environment" pillar of 
the National Security Agency's zero-trust guidelines. (15 March 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/threat-intelligence/150kplus-uae-network-devices-apps-exposed-online"&gt;150K+ UAE Network Devices &amp;amp; Apps Found Exposed Online&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Misconfigurations, insecure services leave United Arab Emirates organizations and critical infrastructure 
vulnerable to bevy of cyber threats. (14 March 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/heated-seats-advanced-telematics-software-defined-cars-drive-risk"&gt;Heated Seats? Advanced Telematics? Software-Defined Cars Drive Risk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Carmakers are offering all kinds of over-the-air subscriptions and features, many of which benefit the businesses 
that use them. But this also opens up a wider attack surface for vehicle attackers. (13 March 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/ai-models-take-off-leaving-security-behind"&gt;To Spot Attacks Through AI Models, Companies Need Visibility&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rushing to onboard artificial intelligence, companies and their developers are downloading a variety of pretrained 
machine learning models, but verifying security and integrity remains a challenge. (11 March 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/anti-fraud-project-boosts-security-of-african-asian-financial-systems"&gt;Anti-Fraud Project Boosts Security of African, Asian Financial Systems&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Working with countries and organizations in Africa, Asia, and the Middle East, the Tazama project aims to add 
affordable security and trust to the financial infrastructure. (11 March 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — China-linked hackers and DMARC in the Middle East</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-china-linked-hackers-and-dmarc-in-the-middle-east.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-08T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-03-08T17:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-03-08:/2024/week-in-review-china-linked-hackers-and-dmarc-in-the-middle-east.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A China-linked APT known as "Evasive Panda" &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/china-linked-cyber-spies-blend-watering-hole-supply-chain-attacks"&gt;orchestrated sophisticated cyber-espionage campaigns&lt;/a&gt; by 
combining watering-hole tactics—compromising legitimate websites to infect visitors—with supply-chain attacks to 
deliver its modular malware framework, MgBot, which enables downloading additional payloads and data exfiltration. 
MgBot’s plug‑in architecture allows the actor to spy on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A China-linked APT known as "Evasive Panda" &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/china-linked-cyber-spies-blend-watering-hole-supply-chain-attacks"&gt;orchestrated sophisticated cyber-espionage campaigns&lt;/a&gt; by 
combining watering-hole tactics—compromising legitimate websites to infect visitors—with supply-chain attacks to 
deliver its modular malware framework, MgBot, which enables downloading additional payloads and data exfiltration. 
MgBot’s plug‑in architecture allows the actor to spy on targeted organizations—including NGOs, telecoms in Africa, and 
Tibetan communities—leveraging a multi‑vector approach to infiltrate networks and steal sensitive information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Middle Eastern countries — particularly Saudi Arabia and the UAE — are &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/middle-east-leads-in-dmarc-deployment"&gt;leading global DMARC 
adoption&lt;/a&gt;, with about 57% of Saudi and 43% of UAE domains set to 'reject' unauthenticated emails, surpassing the 
approximately 31% adoption rate among Global 2000 firms. Major infrastructure like SPF, DKIM, and DMARC has been 
widely deployed across regional companies, driven by mandates from Google and Yahoo and supported by national 
cybersecurity regulations. While enforcement still lags globally, the Middle East’s momentum promises to curb phishing, 
improve email reliability, and bolster overall email security—marking a significant shift in the region’s cyber posture.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — US gov't pushes memory-safe programming, Cybersecurity Framework 2.0</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-us-govt-pushes-memory-safe-programming-cybersecurity-framework-20.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-03-01T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-03-01T17:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-03-01:/2024/week-in-review-us-govt-pushes-memory-safe-programming-cybersecurity-framework-20.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) has &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/nist-cybersecurity-framework-2-0-4-steps-get-started"&gt;revised the book&lt;/a&gt; on creating a comprehensive 
cybersecurity program that aims to help organizations of every size be more secure. Here's where to start 
putting the changes into action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convincing phishing emails, synthetic identities, and deepfakes all have been &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/ai-powered-threats-cyberattacks-on-infrastructure-pummel-africa"&gt;spotted in …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) has &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/nist-cybersecurity-framework-2-0-4-steps-get-started"&gt;revised the book&lt;/a&gt; on creating a comprehensive 
cybersecurity program that aims to help organizations of every size be more secure. Here's where to start 
putting the changes into action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Convincing phishing emails, synthetic identities, and deepfakes all have been &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/ai-powered-threats-cyberattacks-on-infrastructure-pummel-africa"&gt;spotted in cyberattacks on the 
continent&lt;/a&gt;. 
Applications are increasingly distributed, expanding companies' cloud attack surfaces and &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/pentesting-as-a-service-cloud-applications"&gt;requiring regular testing to 
find and fix vulnerabilities&lt;/a&gt;
— and avoid the risk of a growing sprawl of services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The White House Office of the National Cyber Director &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/us-government-taking-bigger-role-in-software-security"&gt;puts software developers on notice&lt;/a&gt;, calling for a move to 
memory-safe programming languages and the development of security metrics. UNC1549, aka Smoke Sandstorm and Tortoiseshell, 
appears to be the culprit [behind a cyberattack campaign customized for each targeted organization]https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/illusive-iranian-hacking-group-ensnares-israeli-uae-aerospace-and-defense-firms.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — Firms Face SEC Penalties, AI-Created Patches</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-firms-face-sec-penalties-ai-created-patches.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-23T17:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2024-02-23T17:00:00-04:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-02-23:/2024/week-in-review-firms-face-sec-penalties-ai-created-patches.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The SEC’s new breach-disclosure rules empower regulators to impose steep civil penalties—potentially ranging from 
hundreds of thousands up to millions of dollars—for publicly traded companies that fail to report “material” 
cybersecurity incidents in a timely manner. Enforcement tools include injunctions, disgorgement, officer/director bans, 
and escalating per-violation …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The SEC’s new breach-disclosure rules empower regulators to impose steep civil penalties—potentially ranging from 
hundreds of thousands up to millions of dollars—for publicly traded companies that fail to report “material” 
cybersecurity incidents in a timely manner. Enforcement tools include injunctions, disgorgement, officer/director bans, 
and escalating per-violation fines of $5K–$500K, plus costly legal battles, reputational harm, and shareholder suits. 
CISOs &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/orgs-face-major-sec-penalties-failing-disclose-breaches"&gt;face growing personal liability&lt;/a&gt; 
and pressure to build robust processes, document decision-making, secure 
enhanced D&amp;amp;O insurance, and collaborate closely with legal teams to ensure compliance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other stories include, organizations &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/alarm-over-generative-ai-fuels-security-spending-in-middle-east-africa"&gt;boosting cybersecurity budgets&lt;/a&gt;
to tackle data-privacy and cloud-security threats amid speedy adoption of generative AI. Policy holders using certain 
technologies — such as managed detection and response (MDR) services, Google Workspace, and email security gateways — 
&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/insurers-claims-data-recommend-cybersecurity-technologies"&gt;gain premium discounts&lt;/a&gt; from cyber insurers.
The latest ploy by the APT also known as &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/insurers-claims-data-recommend-cybersecurity-technologies"&gt;Charming Cypress targets policy experts&lt;/a&gt;
in the Middle East, Europe, and the US.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google researchers found that their Gemini large language model can automatically generate functional patches for about 
15% of vulnerabilities detected by runtime sanitizer tools, addressing issues like uninitialized memory, race conditions, 
and buffer overflows. The AI system also integrates automated testing, discarding faulty patches that break builds or 
fail to fix the bug—essential for scaling remediation across thousands of findings. As codebases grow and AI-generated 
code becomes more widespread, such &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/ai-patch-ease-developer-operations-workload"&gt;automated patching tools promise to reduce backlog&lt;/a&gt;, 
boost developer productivity, and strengthen application security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, enterprises typically use the Java-like programming language to customize their Salesforce instances, 
but &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cloud-security/misconfigurated-custom-salesforce-apps-expose-corporate-data"&gt;attackers are hunting for vulnerabilities in the apps&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review: Middle East &amp; Africa CISOs see higher budgets</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-middle-east-africa-cisos-see-higher-budgets.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-16T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-16T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-02-16:/2024/week-in-review-middle-east-africa-cisos-see-higher-budgets.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;More than three-quarters of CISOs across the Middle East, Turkey, and Africa are planning to &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/middle-east-africa-cisos-plan-to-increase-2024-budgets-by-ten-percent"&gt;boost their cybersecurity 
budgets&lt;/a&gt; by at least 10% in 2024, driving total regional investment past $6.5 billion. Driving this growth are
escalating cybercrimes — including state-sponsored threats and destructive 'wiper' malware — tighter 
data regulations, and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;More than three-quarters of CISOs across the Middle East, Turkey, and Africa are planning to &lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/middle-east-africa-cisos-plan-to-increase-2024-budgets-by-ten-percent"&gt;boost their cybersecurity 
budgets&lt;/a&gt; by at least 10% in 2024, driving total regional investment past $6.5 billion. Driving this growth are
escalating cybercrimes — including state-sponsored threats and destructive 'wiper' malware — tighter 
data regulations, and rising uncertainty around generative AI — especially in core markets like 
Saudi Arabia and the UAE, which are leading the regional surge.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review: Quishing, Smart Cities, More on Cybersecurity Jobs, and Will We Manage Everything?</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-quishing-smart-cities-more-on-cybersecurity-jobs-and-will-we-manage-everything.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-09T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-09T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-02-09:/2024/week-in-review-quishing-smart-cities-more-on-cybersecurity-jobs-and-will-we-manage-everything.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five of my articles were published this week: Four on Dark Reading and another on README.security (which now defaults to Synack's domain, since they own it). Among the major issues, the cybersecurity jobs market is looking less strong, and companies are looking to managed services to simplify security in …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five of my articles were published this week: Four on Dark Reading and another on README.security (which now defaults to Synack's domain, since they own it). Among the major issues, the cybersecurity jobs market is looking less strong, and companies are looking to managed services to simplify security in a tight market. Meanwhile, QR codes became a trend in late 2023, but are already subsiding. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/endpoint-security/qr-code-quishing-attacks-execs-email-security"&gt;QR Code 'Quishing' Attacks on Execs Surge, Evading Email Security | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The use of QR codes to deliver malicious payloads jumped in Q4 2023, especially against executives, who saw 42 times more QR code phishing than the average employee. (8 February 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/managed-everything-vendors-shifting-to-services"&gt;Managed Everything? Vendors Shift Focus to Services | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More companies are opting for managing complex security capabilities, such as data detection and response. (7 February 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/smart-city-ecosystems-face-cybersecurity-shortfall-as-urban-populations-grow"&gt;As Smart Cities Expand, So Do the Threats | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The systems that make up a smart city ecosystem are not easily secured and require better design and better policy to ensure they are not vulnerable. (6 February 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/pegasus-spyware-targets-jordanian-civil-society"&gt;Pegasus Spyware Targets Jordanian Civil Society in Wide-Ranging Attacks | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the Middle East nation enforces strict cybercrime laws, citizens face crackdowns on free speech with nearly three dozen journalists and lawyers targeted with the NSO Group's spyware. (5 February 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://readme.synack.com/uncertainty-hits-the-cybersecurity-jobs-market"&gt;Uncertainty hits the cybersecurity jobs market | README.security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Despite forecasts of healthy demand for cybersecurity skills, workers see more cuts and a more intense hiring process in their futures. (5 February 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review: Iran's 'Cyber Centers', China's 'Pre-positioning,' and Cloud Identity</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-irans-cyber-centers-chinas-pre-positioning-and-cloud-identity.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-02-02T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-02-02T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-02-02:/2024/week-in-review-irans-cyber-centers-chinas-pre-positioning-and-cloud-identity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lots of global coverage this week. Security researchers exposed Iran's use of cyber centers to hide the activity of their advanced persistent threat (APT) groups, while US officials warned that China's state-sponsored actors were 'pre-positioning' to attack US critical infrastructure, as an adjunct to a physical conflict, such as an …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lots of global coverage this week. Security researchers exposed Iran's use of cyber centers to hide the activity of their advanced persistent threat (APT) groups, while US officials warned that China's state-sponsored actors were 'pre-positioning' to attack US critical infrastructure, as an adjunct to a physical conflict, such as an invasion of Taiwan. Finally, companies are finding tracking identities for cloud services much more difficult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/china-infiltrates-us-critical-infrastructure-ramp-up-conflict"&gt;China Infiltrates US Critical Infrastructure in Ramp-up to Conflict | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Threat actors linked to the People's Republic of China, such as Volt Typhoon, continue to "pre-position" themselves in the critical infrastructure of the United States, according to military and law enforcement officials. (1 February 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/identity-access-management-security/managing-identity-across-clouds-critical-security"&gt;Managing Identity Across Clouds Critical to Enterprise Security | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Privileged access management (PAM) is notoriously difficult to deploy, and companies' increasing use of cloud has made it even more complex. (31 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/iran-cyber-centers-dodge-sanctions-sell-cyber-operations"&gt;Iran's 'Cyber Centers' Dodge Sanctions to Sell Cyber Operations | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Networks of Iranian officials and cyber-offensive specialists have created a variety of cybersecurity contractors in an attempt to dodge sanctions, according to leaked documents. (29 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category><category term="Asia"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review: Magecart attacks in MEA, AI Threats, and Water Sector Cybersecurity</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-magecart-attacks-in-mea-ai-threats-and-water-sector-cybersecurity.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-26T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-26T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-01-26:/2024/week-in-review-magecart-attacks-in-mea-ai-threats-and-water-sector-cybersecurity.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote three articles this week, including efforts by the the US federal government to help critical infrastructure firms to defend against increasing cyberattacks on water suppliers and wastewater utilities. Also, researchers are delving into the security risks associated with the rapid adoption of large language models, indicating that many …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote three articles this week, including efforts by the the US federal government to help critical infrastructure firms to defend against increasing cyberattacks on water suppliers and wastewater utilities. Also, researchers are delving into the security risks associated with the rapid adoption of large language models, indicating that many companies may not have fully assessed the security implications for their operations. Finally, skimming attacks on e-commerce sites — frequently referred to as Magecart attacks — are now targeting Middle Eastern retailers with credit-card skimming operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/ics-ot-security/cisa-water-sector-cyber-guide-incident-response"&gt;CISA's Water Sector Guide Puts Incident Response Front &amp;amp; Center | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As cyberattackers increasingly target water suppliers and wastewater utilities, the US federal government wants to help limit the impact of destructive attacks. (24 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/researchers-map-ai-threat-landscape-risks"&gt;Researchers Map AI Threat Landscape, Risks | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With the rush to adopt large language models, companies have not thought through all of the security implications to their businesses. Two groups of researchers tackle the questions. (24 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/magecart-adds-middle-east-retailers-to-long-list-of-victims"&gt;Magecart Adds Middle East Retailers to Long List of Victims | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cybercriminals who conspire to put credit-card skimmers on e-commerce sites have hit some large vendors in the region. (23 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category><category term="Asia"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review: Cloud-Security Consolidation, Cybersecurity in the Middle East &amp; Africa, Cyber Insurance Data</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-cloud-security-consolidation-cybersecurity-in-the-middle-east-africa-cyber-insurance-data.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-19T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-19T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-01-19:/2024/week-in-review-cloud-security-consolidation-cybersecurity-in-the-middle-east-africa-cyber-insurance-data.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote four articles this week. The Charming Kitten-related cyber-espionage group, linked to Iran's Mint Sandstorm APT, is reportedly posing as legitimate journalists and researchers to gather intelligence on the Israel-Hamas war, showcasing a sophisticated method of targeting educators and researchers. I also covered the rise in cyberattacks, which is …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I wrote four articles this week. The Charming Kitten-related cyber-espionage group, linked to Iran's Mint Sandstorm APT, is reportedly posing as legitimate journalists and researchers to gather intelligence on the Israel-Hamas war, showcasing a sophisticated method of targeting educators and researchers. I also covered the rise in cyberattacks, which is likely to lead to an increase in cyber-insurance premiums, reversing the previous decline, as insurers adjust to offset losses from ransomware claims. In terms of regional cybersecurity readiness, Africa and the Middle East are leading their economic peers but still lag behind on the global stage, with recommendations for investing in updated technologies and patching processes to enhance cyber resilience. Finally, the rapid shift to cloud-native operations among companies has spurred consolidation in the cloud security sector, driven by the need for greater visibility and protection, the benefits of AI, and venture capitalists seeking safer investments amid economic uncertainties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/microsoft-iran-mint-sandstorm-apt-blasts-educators-researchers"&gt;Microsoft: Iran's Mint Sandstorm APT Blasts Educators, Researchers | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Charming Kitten-related cyber-espionage group is posing as legitimate journalists and researchers to get intel on the Israel-Hamas war. (19 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/cyberattacks-rise-likely-ending-insurance-rate-declines"&gt;With Attacks on the Upswing, Cyber-Insurance Premiums Poised to Rise Too | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Insurers doubled premiums in late 2021 to offset losses from ransomware claims. With attacks rising again, organizations can anticipate a new round of increases. (18 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/africa-middle-east-lead-peers-cybersecurity-lag-globally"&gt;Africa, Middle East Lead Peers in Cybersecurity, but Lag Globally | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Both regions score above average compared to similar sized economies, but investing in updated technologies and patching processes would help cyber resilience globally. (16 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cloud-security/zero-trust-ai-and-capital-markets-drive-consolidation-in-cloud-security"&gt;Zero Trust, AI, Capital Markets Drive Consolidation in Cloud Security | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Companies that quickly shifted to cloud-native operations are looking for greater visibility and protection — and AI benefits — while an uncertain economic future has venture capitalists looking toward safety. (15 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category><category term="Africa"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review: More on Passkeys, War &amp; Cyberinsurance</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-more-on-passkeys-war-cyberinsurance.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-12T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-12T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-01-12:/2024/week-in-review-more-on-passkeys-war-cyberinsurance.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just had a couple of article publish this week. The interest in passkeys seems high, so I explored what developers need to be doing to implement passkeys. In addition to that, I covered the likely impact of the settlement of Merck's cyber insurance providers with the pharmaceutical company.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/war-or-not-cyber-insurers-still-hashing-out-exclusion"&gt;War …&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I just had a couple of article publish this week. The interest in passkeys seems high, so I explored what developers need to be doing to implement passkeys. In addition to that, I covered the likely impact of the settlement of Merck's cyber insurance providers with the pharmaceutical company.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/war-or-not-cyber-insurers-still-hashing-out-exclusion"&gt;War or Cost of Doing Business? Cyber Insurers Hashing Out Exclusions | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Following a settlement over Merck's $700 million claims over NotPetya damages, questions remain about what constitutes an act of war for cyber-insurance policies. (11 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/application-security/new-developer-tools-necessary-passkey-adoption"&gt;New Developer Tools Necessary to Boost Passkey Adoption | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passwordless technology that simplifies online access and identity has captured plenty of interest, but it needs to be built first. Developer tools that help add passkeys into Web applications pave the way. (10 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category><category term="Africa"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review: Data Privacy Regs, Passkeys and 2 Cyber Threats</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2024/week-in-review-data-privacy-regs-passkeys-and-2-cyber-threats.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2024-01-05T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2024-01-05T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2024-01-05:/2024/week-in-review-data-privacy-regs-passkeys-and-2-cyber-threats.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! I took off running this year with four articles published to &lt;em&gt;Dark Reading&lt;/em&gt;, including two forward looking articles I wrote last year: First, covering the privacy landscape facing companies, and second, technical advice on how to get up and running with passkeys, which are more convenient and …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! I took off running this year with four articles published to &lt;em&gt;Dark Reading&lt;/em&gt;, including two forward looking articles I wrote last year: First, covering the privacy landscape facing companies, and second, technical advice on how to get up and running with passkeys, which are more convenient and increase security. Finally, I covered two threats reported this week, including the Apache ERP vulnerability and the sale of a remote access trojan (RAT) in the Middle East.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyberattacks-data-breaches/syrian-threat-group-peddles-destructive-silverrat"&gt;Syrian Threat Group Peddles Destructive SilverRAT | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Middle Eastern developers claim to be building a new version of the antivirus-bypassing remote access Trojan (RAT) attack tool. (5 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/vulnerabilities-threats/apache-erp-0day-underscores-dangers-of-incomplete-patches"&gt;Apache ERP Zero-Day Underscores Dangers of Incomplete Patches | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Apache fixed a vulnerability in its OfBiz enterprise resource planning (ERP) framework last month, but attackers and researchers found a way around the patch. (4 January 2024).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/identity-access-management-security/how-to-get-started-using-passkeys"&gt;Getting Started With Passkeys, One Service at a Time | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Passkeys help do away with passwords for logging into websites and cloud services. This Tech Tip outlines ways to get started. (3 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cyber-risk/localization-mandataes-ai-regs-pose-major-data-challenges-in-2024"&gt;Localization Mandates, AI Regs to Pose Major Data Challenges in 2024 | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;With more than three-quarters of countries adopting some form of data localization and, soon, three-quarters of people worldwide protected by privacy rules, companies need to take care. (2 January 2024)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category></entry><entry><title>Week in Review — Cybersecurity Workforce Gap; Efforts to Advance Cybersecurity in Africa</title><link href="https://robertlemos.com/2023/week-in-review-cybersecurity-workforce-gap-efforts-to-advance-cybersecurity-in-africa.html" rel="alternate"></link><published>2023-12-29T17:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2023-12-29T17:00:00-05:00</updated><author><name>Robert Lemos</name></author><id>tag:robertlemos.com,2023-12-29:/2023/week-in-review-cybersecurity-workforce-gap-efforts-to-advance-cybersecurity-in-africa.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm taking the week off, but a couple of my articles written last week ended up publishing during the break. The chasm between what businesses are willing to pay cybersecurity-skilled workers (and their expectations of what skills a worker has) continues to crash into what workers think they are worth …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I'm taking the week off, but a couple of my articles written last week ended up publishing during the break. The chasm between what businesses are willing to pay cybersecurity-skilled workers (and their expectations of what skills a worker has) continues to crash into what workers think they are worth. The result is cybersecurity executives wanting more professionals, but not being able to pay the required amount. Continuing to ramp up my coverage of the Middle East and Africa region for Dark Reading, I covered the efforts among African nations to convert their young populations into highly skilled workers, including in cybersecurity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/cyber-employment-2024-sky-high-expectations-fail-businesses-job-seekers"&gt;Cyber Employment 2024: Sky-High Expectations Fail Businesses &amp;amp; Job Seekers | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unreasonable requirements, low salaries, and a lack of commitment to training leaves businesses unable to hire their perfect cybersecurity pros. So, is there really a workforce "shortage"? (26 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.darkreading.com/cybersecurity-operations/african-organizations-aim-to-fix-cybersecurity-in-2024"&gt;African Organizations Aim to Fix Cybersecurity in 2024 | Dark Reading&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The continent suffers $3.5 billion in losses every year, lending momentum to efforts to train a generation of cybersecurity professionals. (26 December 2023)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Week in Review"></category><category term="Cybersecurity"></category><category term="Dark Reading"></category><category term="articles"></category><category term="Africa"></category></entry></feed>